Andre Young

17102 Ashton CT Accokeek MD, 20607

Cell: (202) 369-8494 • andrejyoung@gmail.com • https://andreyoung.dev • https://github.com/youngai

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

Senior Software Engineering Manager with over 20 years of development and leadership experience with a commitment to delivering quality solutions that exceed expectations. I have worked on and led a variety of projects and products over my career both greenfield and long lived critical systems. I am looking for an environment that I can have a positive impact on both the organization, the projects/products and the users these projects ultimately service.

SKILLS

I have acquired a number of relevant skills over the years that contribute to my success.

Agile Project Management Automated Testing Microservice Architecture

Requirements gathering CI/CD RESTful Services

Coaching/Mentorship JavaScript / TypeScript GraphQL
Performance Management HTML Node.js

Team/Community building CSS ASP.NET & ASP.NET Core

AWS Certified React

Git Gatsby / NextJS / CRA
Docker Angular / AngularJS

PROJECTS

Conveyor Belt

• Lead multiple teams to create Conveyor Belt, an internal meta-platform that helps internal Capital One engineers to better discover and utilize internal Capital One platforms while simultaneously reducing cycle times from inception to delivery and improving governance of artifacts going into controlled environments such as production. This project is powered by a number of key concepts such as a configurable workflow and plugin model that allowed for each platform to customize their experience while providing a uniformed look and feel across all the supported platforms.

Commercial Real Estate Management (CREM)

• Led a team of engineers along with a product owner and designer to create a two sided marketplace for landlords and renters. This system enabled landlords to manage multiple portfolios of properties, buildings and units. CREM also enabled a quick and secure way to pay their rent, request services and communicate with their landlords. The application architecture was designed to address a number of concerns including scale, speed of development, security and available tooling and requirements along with the existing knowledge and skills of the team.

Exploration & Space Communications (ESC) Public Website

- Led a team of developers, a system administrator and a designer to bring to life and expand an existing design with a tight delivery date and limited specifications. Designed a deployment and management system for the content managers to preview their changes and deploy on demand to dev, staging and/or production environments.
 - Client/UI Created using Gatsby with Material-UI components. This stack was chosen for the front end to enhance SEO, faster load times and to support lower bandwidth devices.
 - CMS Strapi was chosen as the CMS layer by a previous developer and was approved by management. At
 the time of implementation this product was in a Beta release which proved to be a complication but one that
 we worked around.
 - Server The project required the ability to send emails. ASP.NET Core was chosen to provide the server layer given the experience level of the system administrator that would be providing support

ANDRE YOUNG 2/5

 Orchestration layer - This layer is written in NodeJS due to its flexible nature and easy integration with other command line tools (Gatsby, .NET Core, etc) needed to orchestrate the building and deployment to various environments.

o https://esc.gsfc.nasa.gov/

Symphony

- Designed and implemented a web application to organize, share, and secure project files. This application also tracked frequently asked questions (FAQs), software inventory, hardware inventory, employee onboarding, and much more.
 This application was created and maintained using SCRUM principles with two week iterations. The core application components consist of the following:
 - Client/UI Angular 1.x SPA for the client using a mixture of factories, directives, components and routes based on the best practices found in the Angular 1 Style Guide.
 - Web API –The Web API layer, written in C#, handle requests from the client, coordinating various services to produce a response.
 - Services, Repositories, and Entities These services house the core business logic, data access and data entities
 - Background Service This service handles long running and/or background tasks such as change tracking and cache invalidation, etc. via the Service and Repositories DLLs mentioned earlier.

FLEX

- Designed and implemented a web application to automate and assist financial/resource analysis (RAs) for Space Science Mission Operations (SSMO) of the Astrophysics Projects Division of NASA. This tool provides a consistent way for the RAs to pull and organize financial data. This project saves hundreds of hours of manual effort each month on the part of the RA team and allows them to spend more time analyzing the data.
 - Client/UI Angular 1.x SPA for the client using a mixture of factories, directives, components and routes based on the best practices found in the Angular 1 Style Guide.
 - Web API –The Web API layer, written in C#, handle requests from the client, coordinating various services to produce a response.
 - Services, Repositories, and Entities These services house the core business logic, data access and data entities.

Goddard Review Management System (GRMS 3.0)

- Designed and implemented an internet based application to track project review Request for Action (RFA). This application is designed with three tiers for optimum security and portability.
- The User Interface (UI) employs a user centric design, designed to be intuitive and responsive. AJAX components give instant feedback.
- The Business Logic Layer (BLL) contains object oriented classes that organize all related functionality and encapsulate the majority of the requirements. The BLL also contains notable non-requirement objects such as the application log object which captures system errors and reports them to the programmer and the button object which allows system administrators to create new functionality through the user interface.
- The Data Access Layer (DAL) manages all access to the SQL Server 2008 database. Each object has a stored procedure that manages the searching, adding, deleting, loading and other functionality.

Requirements Mapping Database

- Designed and implemented an internet based application to principally track requirements throughout the life cycle of
 application development. This application also tracks inter relationships between all the principal objects of a web
 application which include but are not limited to the initial user requirements, code objects and functions, database
 tables and fields, user interface pages, and system bugs.
- The back end of this system is powered by a SQL Server 2008 database which employs numerous tables that represent the various objects and their relationships. Each principle object is managed by an intricate stored procedure designed to manage the various functionalities required by the application including adding, editing, deleting, searching, and creating dynamic links to other principle objects

ANDRE YOUNG 3/5

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineering Manager Digital Focus TECH Supervisor: Justin Bachorik

April 2020 – current Capital One

Hours/week: 40

 People Manager and Tech Lead for the Safehouse and Discovery teams at Capital One project building out the Conveyor Belt platform. This responsibility includes providing technical mentorship to the development team, performance management, project planning, collaborating with and presenting to senior management, application architecture and inter team coordination.

IT Manager & App Development Lead Code 450, 444, 480, & 301 Supervisor: Colleen Ponton

July 2012 – April 2020 NASA: ASRC Federal 301-286-4428

Hours/week: 40-45

- Led development effort for PAAC IV Contract. This responsibility includes providing technical mentorship to the
 development team, planning and collaborating with senior management, application architecture and exploring new
 technologies for feasibility.
- Led development effort for Exploration & Space Communications (ESC), Satellite Servicing Projects Division (SSPD) and Space Science Mission Operations (SSMO) support applications. This effort includes maintaining, enhancing and managing the migration of legacy applications. This position also encompases architecting and implementing new applications using the latest technology and proven design principles.
- Initiated and led an internal <u>developer group meetup</u> to share and leverage individual knowledge and skills across multiple contracts and Goddard Space Flight Center (GSFC). The group is also designed to tackle common problems such as redundancy and lack of communication between individual in-house applications.

Senior Application Developer Code 301 & 700 Supervisor: Rob Swartz / Richie Weis **July 2011 – July 2012** NASA: ASRC PRIMUS 301-286-6770 / 301-286-4428

Hours/week: 40

- Upgrade and maintain Code 301's Goddard Review Management System (GRMS 3.0) that tracks Requests for Action (RFA) from the various mission reviews on and off center.
- Analyze and design the next generation configuration management tool (MIS 2.0) to incorporate coding best practices.
- Support Student On-Line Application for Recruiting Interns, Fellows, and Scholars (SOLAR) an online application used by all NASA centers to allow students to apply for, and be selected for internships, fellowships and scholarships using a SQLServer database and ColdFusion 8 front end.

MIS V (Senior Programmer) LRO & Code 301 Supervisor: Richie Weiss

July 2007 – July 2011 NASA: ASRC Federal 301-286-4428

Hours/week: 40

- Researched, designed and built the next generation Goddard Review Management System (GRMS 3.0) that employed modern design principles and tools such as Object Oriented code design, ASP.NET 3.5, AJAX Controls, SQL Server 2008, and other 3rd party tools.
- Manage project milestones and two other employees to maintain workflow and project deadlines.
- Created and maintained software requirement and development tracking and traceability tool which enable both
 programmers and clients to find exactly where requirements are met throughout the application. This tool also
 provides a wealth of information during and after development that greatly increases efficiency and adaptability of the
 software it traces by tracking numerous inter relationships between code, database objects, user interface,
 requirements, etc.

Software Engineer Peace Corps Project Supervisor: Barbara Schipper

May 2007 - July 2007 Systems Management Engineering Inc. 703-525-7500

Hours/week: 40

- Implement modules for Peace Corps' Volunteer Information Database Application Project (VIDA) to transition from MS Access to a .Net 2.0 Winforms application.
- Worked with team members to solve complex problems such as offline data synchronization.
- Create Active Reports using VB.NET.

ANDRE YOUNG 4/5

MIS III (Programmer) GPM & LDCM & LRO Supervisor: Fred Brooks

February 2006 – May 2007 NASA: SGT Inc. 301-286-4428

Hours/week: 40

Tailor large scale Active Server Page (ASP) application (NGIN) that provides Action Items, Configuration
Management, Drawings, and Shared Files along with numerous other modules to meet the requirements of NASA's
Global Precipitation Measurement Project, Landsat Data Continuity Mission (LDCM) and LUNAR project.

• Add new features to simplify and shorten current procedures.

• Implement changes to code and server in response to and to prevent security threats such as SQL Injection Attacks.

ASP Programmer GPM & LDCM Supervisor: Fred Brooks

April 2005 – February 2006 NASA: **PRISM Inc.** 301-286-4428

Hours/week: 40

- Tailor large scale ASP application (NGIN) that provides Action Items, Configuration Management, Risk Management, Drawings, Shared Files, and numerous similar modules to meet the requirements of NASA's Global Precipitation Measurement Project, Landsat Data Continuity Mission (LDCM) and LUNAR project.
- Debug and rewrite pages that are not working correctly.
- Add new features to simplify and shorten current procedures.

Provide user administrator duties.

Programmer Office of Multi-Media Services Supervisor: Jeffrey Hammer

January 2003 – April 2005 Dept. of State: **Viatech Inc.** 202-647-7781

Hours/week: 40

- Designed and coded an online application to order, track and manage certificates using ASP, SQL Server and JavaScript.
- Test and provide feedback on current and upcoming Viatech applications.
- Provide and research new ideas for applications.
- Researched and planned for the creation of an office wide system that will track new jobs, estimate job costs, track user time spent on each job, along with materials to gather the true cost of each job.

Document Specialist Office of Multi-Media Services Supervisor: Jeffrey Hammer

May 2002 – January 2003 Dept. of State: **Viatech Inc.** 202-647-7781

Hours/week: 40

- Created layouts and posters using Photoshop 7.0, Illustrator 10.0, and PageMaker7.0.
- Maintained Multi-Media Services supply stock using a Microsoft Excel spreadsheet application that I created.
- Light PC trouble shooting for the Customer Service branch of Multimedia office

Student Intern Office of Multi-Media Services Supervisor: Phyllis Smith

June 1999 – May 2002 Department of State 202-647-1105

Hours/week: 40

- Set up a database using MS Access along with an intranet web site to request certificates.
- Set up a database using MS Access to organize and track printing jobs.
- Created publication layouts using PageMaker 6.5 and Photoshop 5.0.

EDUCATION

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate

https://www.credly.com/badges/858ce62b-0df5-42c8-bf25-edaf22a38bcehttps://aws.amazon.com/training/course-descriptions/architect/

University of Maryland College Park, MD

Major: Computer Science (Software design and Programming)
Degree: **Bachelors of Computer Science**, December 2002

ANDRE YOUNG 5/5

HONORS & AWARDS

2018 Flight Projects Directorate Peer Award:

• <u>June 2018:</u> **Special Act - Team** "For your valuable contributions to the success of the Flight Projects Directorate, you have been selected as a 2018 Peer Award recipient."

• June 2018: Excellence as Mentor "Under Your Wing "For your extraordinary concern and drive to ensure peers, mentees and the community have the tools necessary to succeed.

Certificate of Appreciation

- <u>December 2014</u>: "In recognition of your continuous efforts to encourage the software developers within the Goddard Space Flight Center to work collaboratively. Through your bi-weekly meetings where developers share their code, tools, and best practices, a new positive culture of learning has flourished."
- December 2014: "In recognition of your contribution and support as a Mentor and participating in the PAAC II Mentorship Program"
- August 2003: "In recognition of your outstanding achievement in support of the US Department of State Multi-Media Services"
- May 2002: "We value very sincerely your dedicated service."

RHG Exceptional Achievement for Engineering Team

• "For dedication and teamwork leading up to the launch of the Raven Technology Module to the International Space Station."

Franklin Award

- February 2002: "In recognition of your contributions to the success of the Chile Declassification Project"
- August 2000: "For dedicated performance that has led to improved customer relations."

REFERENCES

Available upon request